http://www.rhodogroup-rhs.org/membership/privacy/

Yearbooks
Privacy StatementThis privacy statement applies when RCMG receives, holds or otherwise uses Personal Data and explains how we look after your personal information and what we do with it. RCMG is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. Please be assured that we will never sell or exchange your data.Changing your preferences for communicationAt any time, you can change how you hear from us, including by post or telephone, or unsubscribe from electronic communications – please contact sales@placeforplants.co.uk or telephone 01206 299224 to let us know.Why do we collect personal information?You may give us your personal information in order to join as a member, make a donation, participate in an event, or to receive our e-newsletters. The personal information we collect might include your name, address, email address, telephone number, year of birth, payment card or bank details. We collect this information only in connection with specific activities, such as providing membership benefits, processing your membership, donation processing, or sending regular information about our work, our events, opportunities and conservation news. We will only share your information with trusted suppliers to carry out these transactions.How do we use your personal information?• To fulfil your membership application• To process membership subscriptions, donations or other payments• To set up or alter your Direct Debit Instruction via BACS if applicable• To confirm details of your Gift Aid status, if applicable• To post you our publications such as Yearbook, Bulletins, or local branch publications• To send you occasional e-newsletters or local branch e-newsletters about our work and local activities• For in-house research and analysis to ensure our communications are as relevant as possible• In order to process the mailing of the Yearbook and Bulletins we use a trusted mailing company who keep your data secure, and destroy records after each use.Consent and keeping your information up to dateBy disclosing your personal information to us as part of becoming a member of RCMG you give your consent to the collection, storage, processing and use of your personal information by us as described in this privacy statement.As a RCMG supporter, you have control over the accuracy of your personal information. If, at any time, you wish to verify, update or amend the personal information you have provided, you can contact us at the above email and telephone number.Individuals can find out if RCMG holds any personal information about them by making a ‘Subject Access Request’. If RCMG does hold information about you, we will:• give you a description of the information held• tell you why we are holding the information• tell you who the information could be disclosed to• give you a copy of the information.To make a Subject Access Request please send a letter or email (headed ‘Subject Access Request’) to the Group Secretary shown in the Committee listing. RCMG will respond in writing within 1 month of receiving the request.Retention of personal dataRCMG will keep your data only for as long as is necessary to meet the requirements of financial record keeping or for the purposes of historical research.Right to be forgotten:Notwithstanding the requirements to retain personal data as outlined above, you have the right to request deletion of your personal data. To make a Subject Access Request please send a letter or email (headed ‘Request to be Forgotten’) to the Group Secretary shown in the Committee listing.SecurityYour personal data is held securely by RCMG administration officers and by your branch membership chairman/secretary, and will not be shared without your permission. Our website uses PayPal as a gateway for secure transactions with us. Card payment transactions are encrypted and original documents are destroyed as soon as transactions are processed.Changes to this Privacy StatementBy giving your Personal Data to RCMG, you agree to accept our privacy statement as amended from time-to-time. You will be deemed to have accepted any amendments to the statement if you continue to provide personal information to RCMG after a new version of the statement is published.We recognise the importance of privacy to our supporters and visitors will keep this statement under review and any changes made from time to time will be posted on this website.Privacy and use of our WebsiteYou should be aware that if you follow a link to another website and give any personal information to another company, the uses to which that information may be put will be determined by that company's privacy policy.RCMG Cookie PolicyThe RCMG website uses Cookies, including Google Analytics which enables Google to gather data on our visitors, in order for us to better understand interaction with our website and make improvements. A ‘cookie’ is a piece of information, like a tag, which some websites create on your PC. Our cookies allocate each user of this website with a random number. This procedure does not entail the collection of any personal information. Our cookies will not be used to analyse your visits to other websites or track any internet searches you may undertake whilst on this website.What if I don't want to accept cookies?Your browser lets you choose whether to accept, not to accept or to be warned before accepting cookies. These settings can be found in the advanced preferences.© 2020 Rhododendron, Camellia & Magnolia Group
Registered Charity number 1161254
Email
info@rhodogroup-rhs.org
Patron: HRH The Prince of Wales
Announcements
Members forum
Instagram
Twitter
